# Rajendra Kumar 🕡 Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, SQL, HTML, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Eclipse, STS, Oracle..



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: Wipro Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: ,Application Programming,Application Maintenance,Project Management,Requirement Analysis,Solution

Architecture, Java, SQL, HTML, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Eclipse, STS, Oracle, micro services

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

### **Summary**

Having 4+ Years of Experience as a Software Engineer in the IT industry.

Hands on experience in Java, Spring Boot Framework, Micro services and JPA.

Sound knowledge of Collection framework, OOPS Concept, Exception Handling, Multiple Threading.

Hands on experience in Oracle, MySQL Databases.

Hands on experience in J2EE Design Patterns.

Good Knowledge in XML and Restful Web Services.

Good Knowledge in Micro services and AWS.

## **Work Experience**

**Wipro** as Software Developer Aug 2019 to Till Date

**Wipro** as Software Engineer -Java Aug 2019 to Jun 2020

developing the micro services and integrate with the other micro services using spring cloud

**Aricent** as Software Engineer Feb 2016 to Aug 2019

As per the requirement develop the feature and deploy them. worked with production issue as well

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Rajasthan Technical University, Jaipur in 2015

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
WINDOWS 10		2020	4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
Java, SQL, Html		2020	4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
Servlets, Jsp, Jdbc		2017	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Apache Tomcat, JBOSS		2020	4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate		2020	2 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
Eclipse, STS		2020	4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
ORACLE 10G		2019	3 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
MICRO SERVICES		2020	1 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Rajasthani				

# **Projects**

Project Title: WeBuy

Client: wipro

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2019 - Jun 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bangalore

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Spring Boot, Core Java,

Role Description: Developing the feature according the requirement

Project Details: This modification allows Wipro to raise the request for the Laptop and Desktop. We buy is an internal project.

Wipro employees can request for Laptop and other accessories like Ram, Mouse, Hard-Disk and Keybord using this

application.

Project Title: Inmarsat

Client: Cisco

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Aug 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bangalore

Role: Programmer Team Size: 8

Skill Used: core java, Java Web Services, PLSQL,

Role Description: Developing the feature according the requirement

Project Details: Inmarsat is a British satellite telecommunications company, offering global mobile services. It provides telephone and data services to users worldwide, via portable or mobile terminals which communicate with ground stations through thirteen geostationary telecommunications satellites.

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time